<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about Mobile)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/cat_mobile.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:13:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>GeoRSS and Live Search for Mobile</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/georss-and-live-search-for-mobile.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully by now you all have v3.0 of the Live Search client, and are
enjoying the new features (web search, weather, and collections). I'd
like to talk about collections in this post, but first it is worth
mentioning a couple of changes in this version that are less obvious,
and overcome limitations I have blogged about in the past:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we now have Outlook contact integration. From Outlook contacts you
    can select the "Show on Map" menu option to map a contact. Google
    Maps contacts integration is still broken,
    but we can't let that hold us back any longer; we gave them nearly a
    year as well as explicit instructions on what their bug was; if they
    can't get their house in order with all that then too bad for them.
    If you do want to use both GMM and Live Search, then install GMM
    last. Their bug will cause problems with any other software that
    installs menu extensions that is installed after them; if the other
    apps are well-behaved then you can install them before GMM and you
    should be okay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have put back the ability to enter addresses in the search box.
    We have a better geocoder now on the back end and are more confident
    that you will get the results you want when doing this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/georss-and-live-search-for-mobile.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/georss-and-live-search-for-mobile.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 12:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Last Day on Live Search for Mobile</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/last-day-on-live-search-for-mobile.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today is my last official day on the Live Search for Mobile team. I am
moving over to a new team working on some incubating new mobile
initiatives in emerging markets (as a South African ex-pat I can relate
to this). It has been a fun ride and it is hard to let go of the Windows
Mobile client which I think of as 'my baby' (with co-parent Ashley).
There is still so much to do. However, some of the things that I have
been trying to get shipped since September 2006 are finally going out
the door in the upcoming release so I can feel that I have achieved at
least some of what I set out to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll continue blogging here of course, and I expect to blog quite a lot
about the new release once it is out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the WM client team in July 2006, after the MOJAX (mobile
AJAX) project got killed. That left the core group - the Barrel of
Monkeys - without a home. There were five of us - Steve (PM), Ashley and
I (dev), John (test) and Danny (architect). Rather than each go off to
different jobs we decided to try stick together, and managed to find a
home in local search. We had three months to get the v1.0 product out,
and it was a hit! We got an awful lot of fan mail from that (and if you
were a sender, thanks! We've always appreciated the love :-) ).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/last-day-on-live-search-for-mobile.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/last-day-on-live-search-for-mobile.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 12:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why There Are no ARCO Gas Prices</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-there-are-no-arco-gas-prices.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We get gas price data from a 3rd party provider. They in turn get the
data from credit card companies. ARCO does not accept credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a great example of where user-contributed data would be
valuable, and I hope that one day we will be able to extend the feature
to include that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-there-are-no-arco-gas-prices.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2008 12:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We're Hiring!</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/were-hiring.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My team is hiring. The job descriptions are below. PM me if you're
interested:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/were-hiring.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/were-hiring.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Channel 10 Video coming soon!</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/channel-10-video-coming-soon.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;Last week the &lt;a href="http://on10.net/"&gt;Channel 10&lt;/a&gt; team visited us and shot
some video of us demoing the Live Search for Mobile client, including
some of the features of our upcoming release (real soon now!) I'm not
sure when the edited video will be available - I guess after the
release - but will update this posting with a link when it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/channel-10-video-coming-soon.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2008 12:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Live Search for Mobile Saves the Day</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/live-search-for-mobile-saves-the-day.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/peterlau/archive/2008/03/24/live-search-for-windows-mobile-saves-the-day.aspx"&gt;stories like
this...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/live-search-for-mobile-saves-the-day.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 13:31:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Connectivity problems with Live Search on Blackberry</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/connectivity-problems-with-live-search-on-blackberry.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to share this information that one of our Blackberry devs,
Didier, sent to a customer who was having problems as it may be useful
to others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Live Search for BlackBerry is distributed as an independent
third party application, it works only if such applications are
allowed to do network requests, which may depend on both your carrier
network policies and your subscription type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We support three connection modes in Live Search for BlackBerry:
Direct HTTP, BES/MDS and WAP Gateway, but for CDMA devices only Direct
HTTP and BES/MDS are possible (WAP is specific to GPRS/Edge carriers).
BES/MDS is for corporate devices administrated through the company’s
BlackBerry Enterprise Server, Direct HTTP is for individual
subscribers. You can try both modes if you are unsure of your
configuration (in Options &amp;gt; Enter your network configuration
parameters).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But some BlackBerry data plans may be limited to Email &amp;amp; Web browsing
and Live Search will not work in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/connectivity-problems-with-live-search-on-blackberry.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2008 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why There Is No Integration With Outlook Mobile Contacts</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-there-is-no-integration-with-outlook-mobile-contacts.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We often get asked why we don't have a menu item in the Contacts app on
the phone to map a contact, but Google does. The comments can sometimes
be quite disparaging (like what's wrong with you people in Redmond,
anyway?). So here is the tale, told by an idiot, without much sound or
fury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early in 2006 I wrote the code to hook into Contacts. It worked pretty
well, and we planned to ship this in our v2 release in July '07. Shortly
before our release date, Google released an update to their Windows
Mobile map app, and they had the feature. So we immediately decided to
test to make sure we played nicely together.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-there-is-no-integration-with-outlook-mobile-contacts.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-there-is-no-integration-with-outlook-mobile-contacts.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Can't I Enter An Address In The Search Box</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-cant-i-enter-an-address-in-the-search-box.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A common source of confusion for our users is the distinction we make
between 'what' and 'where'. We generally search for 'what' (which is the
text you can enter on the main form), centering the results on the
'where' (which is the location shown just below). If you want to change
the location, &lt;em&gt;or if you want to search for an address&lt;/em&gt;, you need to
click on 'Choose a new location'; you can then enter the address on the
Location screen and click 'Find' (note: the screen shots shown below
come from a test version of the app we run on the desktop; the menus at
the top will be on the bottom on your phone, accessible via the two
softkeys; I just used the desktop version here as it was quicker for
me):
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-cant-i-enter-an-address-in-the-search-box.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/why-cant-i-enter-an-address-in-the-search-box.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2008 13:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Help! My Keyboard Doesn't Work!</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/help-my-keyboard-doesnt-work.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We get a lot of people reporting problems with their hardware keyboards
on phones like the VX6800. When they press the letter keys instead of
letters they get numbers and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this is a problem with the IME (input method editor) in
the phone. IMEs are often customized by the phone OEM or the mobile
operator to add functionality like predictive text input. For a number
of phones, an IME was added that breaks text input from the keyboard
with all .Net Compact Framework apps. In many cases we're the only such
app on the phone, so users understandably think its a bug in our
program. We wish it was - in that case we could fix it - but there
really isn't anything we can do other than complain.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/help-my-keyboard-doesnt-work.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/help-my-keyboard-doesnt-work.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2008 13:39:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>