<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about Management)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/cat_management.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 04:57:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Managing Engineering and Data Science Agile Teams</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/managing-data-science-and-engineering.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is very common in modern software engineering organizations to use agile approaches to managing teamwork. At both Microsoft and eBay teams I have managed have used Scrum, which is a reasonably simple and effective approach that offers a number of benefits, such as timeboxing, regular deployments (not necessarily continuous but at least periodic), a buffer between the team and unplanned work, an iterative continuous improvement process through retrospectives, and metrics that can quickly show whether the team is on track or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science work does not fit quite as well into the Scrum approach. I've heard of people advocating for its use, and even at my current team we initially tried to use Scrum for data science, but there are significant challenges. In particular, I like my Scrum teams to break work down to user stories to a size where the effort involved is under two days (ideally closer to half a day). Yes, we use story points, but once the team is calibrated fairly well its still easy to aim for this. Trying to do this for data science work is much harder, especially when it is research work in building new models which is very open-ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach I have taken with my team is an interesting hybrid that seems to be working quite well and is worth sharing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/managing-data-science-and-engineering.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Data Science</category><category>Management</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/managing-data-science-and-engineering.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 04:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Maslow's Hierarchy and your Team</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/maslow-team.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in a previous post that I would talk about Maslow's &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs"&gt;Hierarchy of Needs&lt;/a&gt; in relation to team health. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maslow described a set of layers of needs with respect to human motivation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;physiological - the basic needs for survival (food, water, shelter, air, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;safety - health, well-being, security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;love/belonging - friends and family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;esteem - respect of others and (more importantly) self-respect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-actualization - becoming the most you can be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;self-transcendence - altruism and given of yourself to others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maslow considered the first four to be necessary for mental health and a pre-requisite for self-actualization
and transcendence.
This hierarchy of needs is a useful model; it's not science but can help us understand shortcomings in ourselves
and others that may need addressing to reach our full potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does this relate to teams and management? We can come up with a similar set of needs for healthy teams 
and team members:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/maslow-team.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/maslow-team.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 14:38:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>1-on-1s can take a hike!</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/1-1s-hike.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you a people manager? Do you enjoy doing 1-1s with your reports? No? Then you're doing them wrong!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-1s are a valuable and important part of both managing your team and becoming a better manager. You should see them as as much for your benefit as for your reports - arguably more so! Not only are you getting the opportunity to keep your reports on track and on a growth path, but it's a great opportunity to get feedback yourself. Unless you're the kind of manager who thinks managing is all about giving orders and having them carried out, in which case this post isn't for you; go enlist or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a number of reasons why managers (and employees) don't enjoy 1-1s:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/1-1s-hike.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/1-1s-hike.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 04:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>