<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about Psychology)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/cat_psychology.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 03:42:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>The 5-Factor Model of Personality</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/personality-and-relationships1.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div tabindex="-1" id="notebook" class="border-box-sizing"&gt;
    &lt;div class="container" id="notebook-container"&gt;

&lt;div class="cell border-box-sizing text_cell rendered"&gt;&lt;div class="prompt input_prompt"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="inner_cell"&gt;
&lt;div class="text_cell_render border-box-sizing rendered_html"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shankar Vedantam has a great NPR show/podcast, &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain"&gt;"The Hidden Brain"&lt;/a&gt;, and occasional appearances on NPR's All Things Considered.  In December he had a show on Evaluating Personality Tests. It was enjoyable, especially the Harry Potter Sorting Hat references, but I felt it was a missed opportunity because of the focus on Myers-Briggs, and the fact that he mentioned the Big-5 model only in passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Myers-Briggs is not taken very seriously in the psychology world, and Vedantam surprised me with spending so much time on it, given his show's focus on research in psychology. On the other hand, the Big-5 model is taken quite seriously, with many studies and papers based on it and evaluating it in various contexts (take a look, for example, at the Oxford University Press book I link to at the end of this post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2017/12/11/569815338/evaluating-personality-tests"&gt;short form NPR segment&lt;/a&gt;, this was the section on Big-5 in its entirety:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;VEDANTAM: Many personality researchers put greater stock in a test known as the Big Five [vs Myers-Briggs]. Grant says the Big Five has lots of peer reviewed data to back it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GRANT: We can predict your job performance, your effectiveness in a team with different collaborators, your likelihood of sticking around in a job versus leaving as well as your probability of your marriage surviving, depending on the personality fit between you and your spouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/personality-and-relationships1.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (6 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/personality-and-relationships1.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 04:35:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>