<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about Computers)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/cat_computers.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:13:21 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Fixing Grub after installing Windows 7</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fixing-grub-after-installing-windows-7.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an MSI Wind on which I run both Windows 7 and Ubuntu. I rarely
use the latter but I like to keep it around and with a 320GB hard drive
its affordable. I have used both the Windows BCD loader and GRUB as my
bootloader at various times (and for those using BCD I highly recommend
&lt;a href="http://neosmart.net/dl.php?id=1"&gt;EasyBCD&lt;/a&gt; as the way to configure it).
Most recently I've been using GRUB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I installed Windows 7 RC and my boot sector got clobbered by
BCD. I had a bit of a had time getting things working again. I first
tried using EasyBCD but this time when trying to boot Ubuntu I ended up
at a GRUB prompt, and I could not access my Ubuntu partition (more
precisely, while "root (hd0,2)" worked, "kernel /vmlinuz" threw errrors
and I could not boot).
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fixing-grub-after-installing-windows-7.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fixing-grub-after-installing-windows-7.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2009 12:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Windows XP "Upgrade"</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-windows-xp-upgrade.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have had all the PCs in our house on Vista since Vista RTMed. This
includes my kids computers, and I like the Vista parental controls
(although I wish they were more comprehensive, combining not only
allowed hours of use but quotas as well). I recently wanted to run my
old copy of the game Creatures, and could not get it to install on
Vista. This was sufficiently frustrating that I decided to switch one PC
back to XP. With all the stories in the blogosphere of people
"upgrading" to XP I thought it would be an interesting contrast to go
back.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-windows-xp-upgrade.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-windows-xp-upgrade.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2008 12:32:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Webkinz Are Evil</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/webkinz-are-evil.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My daughter bought a Webkinz today. These are cheap stuffed animals that
sell at a premium because they have a 'secret code' that allow you to
access the Webkinz website and play games, etc. So of course she wanted
me to set her up to access the site (her PC was locked down to only
allow access to PBS Kids).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go to the site, sign her up, and then sign in. This launches a new
window running an Adobe Flash app. The URL is not even tied to a domain,
but uses a numeric IP address. After watching it flash 'Loading' for a
while, we get a picture of a green field - and nothing happens.
Meanwhile my wife starts complaining from upstairs that the network has
slowed to a total crawl; not only can't she browse but even the LAN is
pretty hosed, with Outlook frozen up while trying to send an e-mail to
the local Exchange server in the next room.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/webkinz-are-evil.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/webkinz-are-evil.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2008 13:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>My Leopard Has Lost Its Spots</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/my-leopard-has-lost-its-spots.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I run a mostly Windows-only setup at home these days. My home setup
consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an SBS2003 server mostly for Exchange mail, which also runs FreeBSD
    in a virtual machine to keep some older services running on Apache
    (primarily the redirector from my domain to Live Spaces and my
    subversion repository).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Windows Home Server, which has taken over the file server
    functionality from SBS2003, as I like its more flexible file
    replication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a media center PC running Vista Ultimate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a kitchen internet appliance running Windows CE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vista Ultimate PCs for each of my kids (and a laptop for the wife)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a desktop PC and a Tablet PC for me with Vista Ultimate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an oldish Mac Mini G4 which was running Leopard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/my-leopard-has-lost-its-spots.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/my-leopard-has-lost-its-spots.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>