<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about General)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/cat_general.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 17:13:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Blogging again</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/blogagain.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, it's been quite a while since I last blogged. My Zite project is not dead; it's actually up and 
running well as a personal aggregator but not ready for multi-user access, and I'm not sure when it
might be. But I've been feeling a bit of an itch to start blogging again so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some material already lined up: I've been teaching an introductory data science bootcamp at
work and thought the notebooks from that could be useful blog posts in and of themselves. So I'll
start slowly publishing those while I write some new material. I'm also going to expand the scope 
of this blog; I'll still cover some tech topics but I',m going to fold in the content from my
dormant math blog and retire it; this may inspire me to do some math blogging again. And I'll be 
throwing in some stuff on management and psychology too. So this will be a mishmash living up to 
the random forest name. I'll use categories to make it more accessible for those only interested
in specific topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More soon!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/blogagain.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Monkeyin’ Around</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/monkeyin-around.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;My partner in crime on Live Search for Mobile, Ashley, has started a
coding blog, which is much more interesting than mine. He's currently
very into functional programming but with a C# bent - basically a C#
schemer - and there's some cool stuff he's been playing around with in
.Net 2.0 and 3.0. &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ashleyf/"&gt;Check it out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/monkeyin-around.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 12:20:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Functional Synchronicity</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/functional-synchronicity.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's been some weird synchronicity going on recently. It started a
few weeks back at work. Earlier this year I wrote a compiler for
Javascript, and this resulted in a conversation with a workmate about
virtual machines. I mentioned the SECD machine and &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0133315797/wishwatcher-20/"&gt;Henderson's seminal
book&lt;/a&gt;
from 1980 on functional programming. My workmate was interested enough
to order a copy, and we've had a number of conversations about
functional programming (which I haven't done in 20 years). At some point
in this process I ended up getting the &lt;a href="http://labs.google.com/papers/mapreduce-osdi04.pdf#search=%22map%20reduce%22"&gt;Google paper on
map/reduce&lt;/a&gt;,
and the paper on &lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/~simonpj/tmp/history.pdf#search=%22history%20of%20Haskell%22"&gt;a history of
Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.
A few days later &lt;a href="http://www.joelonsoftware.com/items/2006/08/01.html"&gt;Joel wrote about map/reduce and
Javascript&lt;/a&gt; on his
blog. Then I ended up almost inadvertently getting a copy of Danny
Hillis' &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0262580977/wishwatcher-20/"&gt;Connection
Machine&lt;/a&gt;
book.  Today I read &lt;a href="http://www.ericsink.com/entries/LarryO.html"&gt;Eric Sink's posting about multicore CPUs and
Erlang&lt;/a&gt;, in which he also
mentioned &lt;a href="http://knowing.net"&gt;Larry O'Briens blog&lt;/a&gt; - so I head over
there and the &lt;a href="http://www.knowing.net/PermaLink,guid,beab1a93-151b-44b1-9d5e-a61f077ec036.aspx"&gt;third posting
down&lt;/a&gt;
discusses a problem very similar to the deadlock issue I just posted
about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows what it all means? Maybe its time to learn
&lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/fsharp/fsharp.aspx"&gt;F#...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/functional-synchronicity.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 10:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>This is s-o-o-o true!</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/this-is-s-o-o-o-true.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out this &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VAGr3mVVUwE&amp;amp;search=microsoft%20ipod"&gt;spoof
video&lt;/a&gt;
about if Microsoft designed the iPod packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very funny, particularly as it is so spot on! Probably because it
comes from Microsoft marketing people.  Even though I personally
wouldn't buy an iPod (I have an 8Gb Zen Micro, and can't wait for the
12Gb version - I want small on the outside but big on the inside).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/this-is-s-o-o-o-true.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2006 11:55:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Digital Reflection</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/digital-reflection.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been going through old CD-R discs of mine with a view to reburning
them on DVD-R to safe some space and generally clean them up. It's
amazing what I'm finding - things that I had totally forgotten having
written. For example, I found a SNMPv1/v2 MIB compiler and browser that
I wrote back in 1995. Until I saw it I had no recollection that I even
did that! After some reflection it all came back. In May 1995 I started
Open Mind Solutions with two friends from university days. Our plan was
to do work for hire to finance the development of a software product. At
that stage I had quite a bit of experience with SNMP, having recently
implemented RMON while working for Mosaic Software. It seemed that there
was a lack of good network management software, and what was available
was hugely expensive (HP OpenView pretty much had the market). We felt
that we could build a worthy competitor to OpenView based on FreeBSD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/digital-reflection.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/digital-reflection.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2005 11:57:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>