<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graham Wheeler's Random Forest (Posts about mathjax)</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/categories/mathjax.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 23:30:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>A Christmas Carroll</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/a-christmas-carroll.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Christmas day, 1877, Lewis Carroll, author of the Alice books,
entertained two bored young girls by inventing a new game that he called
Word Links: given two words, change one word to the other by changing a
single letter at a time with the intermediate steps all being valid
words themselves. For example, to change "cold" to "warm", one can use
the steps "cord", "card", "ward". Carroll later popularised this form of
puzzle in a series of articles in Vanity Fair magazine, changing the
name to Doublets - from the "double, double, toil and trouble" witches'
incantation in Shakespeare's Macbeth.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/a-christmas-carroll.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/a-christmas-carroll.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 05:11:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Gym Locker Paradox</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-gym-locker-paradox.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It happens so often - you go to your section of the gym change room, and
there is just one other person there, and they are using the locker next
to yours and blocking the way. I noticed this a long time ago, and
noticed that others noticed it too, referring to Murphy’s law, or “just
my luck”, or some such explanation. Why does it happen so often?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I call this the &lt;em&gt;Gym Locker Paradox&lt;/em&gt;. It is related to a much more well
known paradox, the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Birthday_paradox"&gt;Birthday
Paradox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which is
commonly formulated as a puzzle: how many people do you need to have in
a room together before the odds are better than even that two share the
same birthday?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-gym-locker-paradox.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-gym-locker-paradox.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2011 14:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Fibonacci ties it all together</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fibonacci-ties-it-all-together.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past few posts I have discussed a diverse set of topics, from
number representation to recurrence relations, Pythagorean triples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these topics are related, and this is particularly illustrated
when we consider the work of Leonardo of Pisa, better known as Fibonacci
(from the Latin “de filiis Bonacci”, or “of the family of Bonacci”).
Fibonacci was born in 1175, in Pisa, Italy, shortly after the start of
the construction of the famous leaning tower. The city of Pisa was a
maritime republic which had its own colonies, including Bugia (in modern
day Algeria), where Leonardo’s father moved in 1192 to be a clerk in the
customs house. It was here that Fibonacci became acquainted with the
Hindu numerals and zero, and where his Muslim teacher introduced him to
the the great book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://magimathics.com/much-ado-about-nothing"&gt;Al-Jabr
wal-Muqabalah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.
Fibonacci subsequently travelled broadly, where he learnt from
mathematicians of different cultures. Around 1200 he returned to Pisa
and began work on his masterpiece &lt;em&gt;Liber Abaci&lt;/em&gt;, which was published in
1202, and begins with these words:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fibonacci-ties-it-all-together.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/fibonacci-ties-it-all-together.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Horn of Gabriel</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-horn-of-gabriel.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href="http://bible.cc/revelation/11-15.htm"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;And the seventh angel sounded
[his horn]; and there were great voices in heaven, saying, The kingdoms
of this world are become the kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ;
and he shall reign for ever and ever.”&lt;/em&gt; (Revelations 11.15, King James
Edition)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Christian and Islamic folklore, it is the angel Gabriel who is
considered to be the seventh angel, who announced the coming of
judgement day. An angel with such a huge responsibility clearly needs an
instrument worthy of the task, and indeed there is one: Gabriel’s horn,
also known as Torricelli’s trumpet, after its discoverer, Evangelista
Torricelli, a student of Galileo. Gabriel’s horn has infinite surface
area but finite volume, and is described the rotating the curve
\(y=\frac{1}{x}\) for \(x \geq 1\) around the \(x\) axis.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-horn-of-gabriel.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-horn-of-gabriel.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 14:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More on Pythagoras</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-pythagoras.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pythagoras is known for two great contributions to mathematics – he
established the need for formal proofs instead of just conjecture and
rules of thumb, and he established the existence of the irrationals. In
popular culture of course, Pythagoras is more well known for the
Pythagorean theorem – that the square of the hypotenuse of a right
angled triangle is the sum of the squares of the other two sides – but
this was one of the oldest known results in mathematics and in fact
predates Pythagoras by as much as a thousand years. Nonetheless,
Pythagoras provided a formal proof, and the result led him to ask
whether there were rational numbers that worked in the case where the
hypotenuse had the length two. That is, what was the fractional
representation of the square root of two? Pythagoras managed to show
there was none, leading to the discovery of the irrational numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His proof was quite simple. Assume that \(\sqrt{2}\) can be
expressed as a fraction \(\frac{a}{b}\) of two whole
numbers \(a\) and \(b\). Assume these are the two smallest
such whole numbers – that is, they have no common divisor allowing the
fraction to be further reduced. Then:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-pythagoras.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-pythagoras.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 11:12:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Primal Soup</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/primal-soup.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/images/image9.png" style="float:right;size:35%;margin:10px"&gt;&lt;img alt="image" src="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/images/image_thumb9.png" title="image"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number theory really began with Euclid, around 300BC, in books 7 through
9 of his masterwork, &lt;em&gt;The Elements&lt;/em&gt;. It is here that we find the
original definitions of odd and even numbers, prime and composite
numbers, perfect numbers (numbers which are the sum of their factors,
e.g. 6 = 3 + 2 + 1), and more. But the greatest achievements of all were
his proofs that composite numbers are the products of primes, that this
factorization is unique, and that there are an infinity of primes. Most
introductory algebra or number theory classes cover these three great
proofs, but they are worth revisiting for those who may have forgotten.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/primal-soup.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/primal-soup.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 14:54:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Archimedes counts the sand</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/archimedes-counts-the-sand.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="http://www.magimathics.com/babylonian-numbers-in-60-seconds"&gt;previous
post&lt;/a&gt;
I described the Babylonian/Sumerian sexagesimal (base 60) counting
system. Unlike this system, most cultures adopted a base 10 counting
system due to the natural inclination to count with the fingers (leading
to the term &lt;em&gt;digits&lt;/em&gt;). Less common were quinary (base 5) systems, but
vigesimal (base 20) were not unusual - for example, this was widespread
in native American culture, including (with a novel variation) the
Mayans. Duodecimal (base 12) has also played a role; we still have
remnants in the groupings of dozens and gross.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/archimedes-counts-the-sand.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/archimedes-counts-the-sand.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 14:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>More on Diophantus and Fermat</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-diophantus-and-fermat.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="http://magimathics.com/monkeying-around"&gt;previous
post&lt;/a&gt; I
wrote about how Fermat scribbled his famous “last theorem” in the margin
of Diophantus’ &lt;em&gt;Arithmetica&lt;/em&gt;. This is called Fermat’s last theorem not
because it was the last thing Fermat wrote but because of all the
incomplete theorem’s we know were left by Fermat it was the last to be
proved, taking about 350 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section of the book where Fermat wrote his comment was on finding
&lt;em&gt;Pythagorean triples&lt;/em&gt;: square numbers whose sums also form squares. Such
numbers can be the sides of Pythagorean (right-angled) triangles, the
most well know being 3-4-5.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-diophantus-and-fermat.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/more-on-diophantus-and-fermat.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 04:06:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mathematics of Toilet Rolls</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-mathematics-of-toilet-rolls.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the late 1980s I was contracted to write some software for a company
that produced video-based educational systems. They had video cassette
machines that had been modified to interface with a PC, which could send
instructions to the VCRs such as play, stop, fast forward, and rewind.
The educational programs consisted of short recorded segments which
typically ended with a question, and based on the answer the user
provided they wanted to continue play at different portions of the tape.
The software they wanted me to write was meant to be able to be given a
current position (i.e. play time) and advance to a new position. For
example I might be told that they are at minute 8 currently and want to
resume play at minute 12.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-mathematics-of-toilet-rolls.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/the-mathematics-of-toilet-rolls.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 14:36:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Babylonian numbers in 60 seconds</title><link>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/babylonian-numbers-in-60-seconds.html</link><dc:creator>Graham Wheeler</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;My 5 year old daughter wanted to heat something up in the microwave. I
suggested she use a minute, and she asked me how to enter that. I said
enter 1, 0, 0, Start. “But when mom tells me to do a minute she says 6,
0, Start”, she responded. I wasn’t sure how to explain to her that 1:00
minute is the same as 60 seconds; microwaves are confusing enough to her
as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why are there are 60 seconds in a minute? Why not 100? The answer
lies about 4000 years ago, in some of the earliest known mathematics, of
Sumeria and Babylon. The Sumerians and later the Babylonians used a
&lt;em&gt;sexagesimal&lt;/em&gt; (base 60) number system for their astronomy (although they
used decimals for day-to-day applications). They had no way to represent
non-whole numbers other than as fractions, and 60 was a convenient base
as it has a large number of factors; in particular it can represent 1/2,
1/3, 1/4, 1/5, and 1/6 all with whole numerators. In fact sexagesimal
notation can be used to exactly represent any fraction in which the
denominator has prime factors of 2, 3, and/or 5 (as these are the prime
factors of 60), with a finite number of symbols.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/babylonian-numbers-in-60-seconds.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>mathjax</category><guid>https://www.grahamwheeler.com/posts/babylonian-numbers-in-60-seconds.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 14:09:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>